<!DOCTYPE ui:UiBinder SYSTEM "http://dl.google.com/gwt/DTD/xhtml.ent">
<ui:UiBinder xmlns:ui="urn:ui:com.google.gwt.uibinder"
             xmlns:g="urn:import:com.google.gwt.user.client.ui"
             xmlns:wg="urn:import:edu.mit.scansite.client.ui.widgets.general">
    <g:HTMLPanel>
        <h2>Database Search Tutorial</h2>
        <wg:MessageDisplayWidget ui:field="messageDisplayWidget"/>

        <h3>Search a Sequence Database for Motifs</h3>
        <p>This program searches all proteins in a selected (subset of a) database for
            matches to a motif or a selection of motifs.
        </p>
        <ol>
            <li>
                First of all, please select a "Search Method":
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Choose
                        <b>Database Motif</b>
                        to search the database for occurrences of one Scansite motif. A listbox will
                        be displayed that allows you to choose a motif.
                        <center>
                            <a href="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_singleMotif.png" target="_blank">
                                <img src="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_singleMotif_s.gif"
                                     alt="Search database for a single motif"/>
                            </a>
                        </center>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Choose <b>Input Motif</b> to search the database for occurrences of
                        your motif. You will have to choose a motif-file from your filesystem
                        and enter a motif name. Detailed instructions about how to create a
                        motif file are given on the <a href="#faq">FAQ</a> page.
                        <center>
                            <a href="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_inputMotif.png" target="_blank">
                                <img src="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_inputMotif_s.gif"
                                     alt="Search database for an uploaded motif"/>
                            </a>
                        </center>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        If you have insufficient information to make a full matrix of
                        binding affinities, but you have a tentative consensus sequence
                        describing your motif, you can still put this into Scansite and
                        search the database for matches. Choose
                        <b>Quick Motif</b>
                        to use
                        this option, and have the consensus sequence available so
                        you can
                        enter it.
                        <br/>
                        Scansite will then construct a rough matrix matching the
                        characteristics of
                        your consensus sequence, and this can be used
                        to
                        search the
                        databases.
                        The results in this case will be less
                        quantitative.
                        However, many users have found this program useful
                        for quickly finding
                        proteins with certain sequence
                        characteristics.
                        <br/>
                        On the page there are two rows of small text boxes, labeled as
                        positions -7 to
                        +7, with 0 being the required fixed position.
                        Start
                        by entering
                        your fixed
                        residue in the only box at position 0.
                        In the
                        primary preference row
                        (top one), enter the
                        residues of your
                        consensus sequence in their position relative to your
                        fixed
                        residue. You can also enter more than one residues in any text
                        box
                        ("ST", for example).
                        Some wildcards are allowed too (they are
                        described on the page).
                        Scansite will give residues in the top row
                        a score of 9.0. For
                        positions with no residue
                        preference, leave it
                        blank or use "X" (any residue).
                        <br/>
                        In the secondary preference row (bottom one), you can enter
                        alternative residues at some
                        positions if desired. These will be
                        given a lower score of 4.5, and thus
                        allows
                        you to specify a weaker
                        affinity for some residue types.
                        <center>
                            <a href="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_quick.png" target="_blank">
                                <img src="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_quick_s.gif"
                                     alt="Search database for a pattern-like motif"/>
                            </a>
                        </center>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        You can also search for proteins that match
                        <b>Multiple Motifs</b>
                        . Since this method is
                        incredibly computationally expensive, the
                        search limits you to a maximum
                        of 5 motifs.
                        You can combine your
                        own
                        motifs with scansite motifs if you want.
                        Just select or/and
                        upload
                        motifs and choose a restriction method for your search.
                        Your
                        options
                        are
                        <i>Gap Penalty</i>
                        and
                        <i>Strict Distance Bounds</i>
                        . Using a gap penalty is much faster than specifying strict
                        distance bounds, because it only evaluates a proteins best
                        scoring
                        motif sites, whereas the
                        other method evaluates all
                        combinations of
                        sites that are found.
                        <br/>
                        A high gap penalty adds a penalizes distances between motif
                        sites
                        more than a medium one,
                        and so on.
                        <br/>
                        If choose to use strict distance bounds, you can specify up to
                        three bounds. Please be aware that
                        you have to select the motifs
                        you want to use before you can choose
                        them from the listboxes
                        in
                        this section. Only distance bounds between distinct motifs are
                        permitted, i.e. you have to
                        select two distinct motifs for
                        specifying a bound.
                        <center>
                            <a href="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_multi_gap.png" target="_blank">
                                <img src="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_multi_gap_s.gif"
                                     alt="Search database for multiple motifs, using a gap penalty"/>
                            </a>
                            <a href="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_multi_bounds.png" target="_blank">
                                <img src="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearch_multi_bounds_s.gif"
                                     alt="Search database for multiple motifs, using strict distance bounds"/>
                            </a>
                        </center>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>Select the database to search using the specified motif(s).</li>
            <li>If you are looking for proteins with specific characteristics,
                you can restrict the search to get a shorter list of more relevant
                results. Just click the links next to the input fields to get more
                information on what you are allowed to enter. If you do not want
                to
                specify any restrictions, you can leave all the restriction fields
                blank.
                Unrestricted searches can take a very long time, so we
                recommend
                you to restrict your search
                (especially if you choose to
                search one of the bigger protein databases:
                TrEmbl, or GenPept).
            </li>
            <li>Finally, select how many proteins you want to see in your
                output
                list. If you want to know ALL sites, just download the output file
                from the result page.
            </li>
            <li>Click "Submit" to start the search.</li>
        </ol>

        <p>
            <i>Please be aware that this program can take several minutes to run
                if you select one of the
                larger databases (TrEMBL, Genpept) or if you
                do not restrict your search
                at all.
                Therefore we recommend to restrict
                the number of proteins that are searched
                somehow.
            </i>
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>When the search is finished</b>
            the results will be displayed.
            This page is divided into these groups
            (you can hide each section by
            clicking on its title bar):
        </p>
        <center>
            <a href="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearchResults.png" target="_blank">
                <img src="img/tutorial/tut_dbsearchResults_s.gif" alt="Results of a database search"/>
            </a>
        </center>

        <table style='margin-left:30px;margin-right:30px' border="1">
            <tr>
                <td>
                    <strong>Search Input</strong>
                </td>
                <td>
                    This section sums up your search parameters.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                    <strong>Search Results</strong>
                </td>
                <td>
                    Here, a few numbers that give you an overview of your results are
                    displayed.
                    This includes:
                    <ul>
                        <li>Total Number of Proteins in Database: The number of proteins
                            that are
                            available in the selected database (no restrictions
                            applied).
                        </li>
                        <li>Number of Proteins Returned by Search: The number of
                            proteins
                            used
                            for the search (with restrictions applied). This is the
                            number of
                            proteins
                            that are scanned for the given motif(s).
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Number of Predicted Motif Sites Found: The total number of
                            motif
                            sites found.
                            You will find all these motif sites in the text-file
                            you can
                            download at the
                            bottom of the page. The table below only
                            displays the top
                            <i>x</i>
                            sites
                            (with
                            <i>x</i>
                            being the output-list size you chose). If you performed a
                            multi-motif database search this entry will be replaced by the
                            total number
                            of single motif sites detected and the number of
                            combined sites.
                            Combined sites are
                            combinations of single motif
                            sites that meet the specified restrictions.
                        </li>
                        <li>Median of Scores / Median Absolute Deviation (MAD) of
                            Scores:
                            Two statistical
                            values that give you an impression of about how
                            good/bad a score you
                            are interested
                            in is in comparison to the
                            rest
                            of the results.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                    <strong>Predicted Motif Sites</strong>
                </td>
                <td>
                    The table presented here displays the top motif sites that
                    Scansite
                    predicts.
                    The results are by default sorted by score, but
                    you can also sort
                    them by protein accession,
                    molecular weight,
                    isoelectric point, or site position by clicking on the
                    column's
                    header.
                    Clicking the score will show a histogram of how good this
                    score is
                    relative to all proteins
                    that were scored in the selected
                    database or database subset that you
                    searched. Clicking the
                    ID or
                    accession number will take you to this protein's entry in the
                    database that was searched.
                    The "Scan!"-link will take you to the
                    Protein Scan page where you
                    can directly scan the
                    protein you
                    selected for motifs.
                </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                    <strong>Download Results</strong>
                </td>
                <td>
                    You can download the results (ALL results, not just those that
                    are
                    displayed in the table) in a
                    tab-separated file by using the
                    link
                    provided here.
                </td>
            </tr>
        </table>
    </g:HTMLPanel>
</ui:UiBinder>