<!DOCTYPE ui:UiBinder SYSTEM "http://dl.google.com/gwt/DTD/xhtml.ent">
<ui:UiBinder xmlns:ui="urn:ui:com.google.gwt.uibinder"
	xmlns:g="urn:import:com.google.gwt.user.client.ui" xmlns:wg="urn:import:edu.mit.scansite.client.ui.widgets.general">
	<g:HTMLPanel>
		<h2>Tutorial Overview</h2>
		<wg:MessageDisplayWidget ui:field="messageDisplayWidget" messageDisplayWidgetID="0" />
		<p>
			The sections below give detailed instructions on how to use the programs that make up Scansite.</p>
		<h3>
			Navigation in Scansite 4.0
		</h3>
		<p>
			The navigation bar on the left-hand side of this page allows you to navigate to all static
			sections in Scansite. The list below describes what pages clicking on the navigation
			buttons will bring you to.</p>
		<table style='margin-left:30px;margin-right:30px'>
			<tr>
				<td>
					<strong>Home</strong>
				</td>
				<td>
					The Scansite 3 landing page ("Home") presents you with an overview of Scansite's features.
					You can either click on one of the links provided here, or navigate to these features by
					using the <i>Scansite Features</i> section in the navigation bar.
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
					<strong>News</strong>
				</td>
				<td>
					We will keep you up-to-date about changes to Scansite in this section of the page.
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
					<strong>Features</strong>
				</td>
				<td>
					The features listed here are described in more detail below.
				</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>
					<strong>Databases and Motifs</strong>
				</td>
				<td>
					The features listed here are described in more detail below.
				</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
		<h3>Scan protein for motifs</h3>
		<p>This program will scan a protein of your choice for all of the motifs in Scansite,
			for a subset of them, or for a motif you prepared and uploaded. You can either use
			a protein entry in public databases (SwissProt, TrEMBL, Genpept, Ensembl, Yeast),
			or your own protein sequence.
		</p>

		<h4>Relevant Options</h4>
		<ol>
			<li>Search a database protein Vs. search your own protein by providing an input sequence</li>
			<li>Choose your sequence motif reference by picking either all motifs, select specific ones or even upload your own motif</li>
			<li>Choose your motif class by selecting either Mammalian or Yeast</li>
			<li>Choose a stringency to determine whether only very good results should be displayed or also matches with worse scores</li>
			<li>Dieplay the protein domains and a table with references to protein families</li>
			<li>Decide whether all results or only those, that have previously been matched by PhosphoSitePlus</li>
			<li>Decide whether the default or an alternative reference proteome should be used for scoring</li>
		</ol>

		<h3>Search a Sequence Database for Motifs</h3>
		<p>This program searches all proteins in a selected (subset of a)
			database for
			matches to a motif or a selection of motifs.</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				Content is under construction and will be available shortly.
			</li>
		</ul>

		<h3>Find Sequence Matches in a Database</h3>
		<p>This program searches all proteins in a selected (subset of a) database for sequence patterns.</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
                Content is under construction and will be available shortly
			</li>
		</ul>
	</g:HTMLPanel>
</ui:UiBinder> 